Alexandre Cela

London I +447463376967 I alexandrecelap@gmail.com I Website I LinkedIn I GitHub

Summary

Highly accomplished Senior Analytics Engineer, with a speciality in Financial Engineering. I have over 6 years of track record setting product teams for success, by building end-to-end data solutions, along with great synergetic team work, that directly impact revenue and operational efficiency. I have become a go to person when it comes to performing data strategy and deploying high ROI data solutions.

Professional Experience

Senior Data Scientist Preqin & Blackrock | London | Aug 2023 - Present

- Led the development of a client-facing BI product for private capital benchmarks, which generated over £2mn in new revenue by performing data wrangling from raw and not curated data into a reliable source for analytics. Played a critical role in the product successfully going native, thanks to expertise and great team collaboration.
- Hands-on building of curated and robust private credit data models through data mining and data integration across multiple uncharted, not curated sources. Including web scraping. Which will be the foundation for future lucrative Index and ETF products.
- Data Strategy: Spearheaded the development of our gold-standard user interaction data model, with dbt and CI/CD execution. 10x the ability to understand user behaviour, perform data storytelling and understand how to increase user LTV.
- Championed a data-driven culture by building analytics self service foundation, and training product managers on how to self serve. Reproducible analysis with streamlit and dataset agnostic python code.
- Identified ROI opportunities through product usage analysis and data storytelling, leading to a new user onboarding survey that boosted new user activation by 35%.
- Management experience: mentoring a junior analyst to 3x team leverage and output

Senior Product Scientist, Indeed Flex | London | May 2021 - Jun 2023

- Owned and revamped a core pay rate uplift logic, reducing costs by 50% while preserving revenue, by connecting data analytics and data storytelling with business outcomes.
- Designed, created, and deployed complex data models using dbt and CI/CD, which
 enabled robust tracking, self-serve analytics, and streamlined experimentation. Including a
 foundational User Intelligence data model, centralising key user information from 8+ tables
 into one, in a simple data model. Reducing friction for PM to obtain key information and for
 Analysts to perform key higher value analysis on user life time value.

Technical Lead, Voc Al (Startup Project) | London | Jun 2023 - Aug 2023

• Led the technical development of a SaaS product using NLP and Generative AI, gaining

hands-on experience with go-to-market strategy and lean engineering team management.

Data Analyst, Nike | Europe HQ | Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

 Automated reporting processes, significantly reducing manual reporting time and improving delivery tracking and success for high-stakes product launches.

Skills & Tools

- Data Modeling & Warehousing: dbt, Snowflake, Snowpark, BigQuery, Redshift, PostgreSQL
- **Programming & ETL:** SQL (Advanced), Python (Advanced), Git, Github, Docker, Web Scraping, JavaScript (beginner), Vibecoding (Windsurf, advanced), n8n (no code)
- Visualization: , Streamlit, Power BI, Tableau, Metabase, Redash
- Cloud Computing Services: GCP
- Other: Generative AI with LLMs, Machine Learning, Data Quality, CI/CD

Education

- Essec Business School, Paris I Sept 2015 Jun 2019
 - Major in Business Analytics & Data Science, Applied Mathematics, and Financial Markets
- Stanford University, Online Certificates
 - Machine Learning (Andrew Ng), Deep Learning, Generative AI with LLMs,
 Fundamentals of Data Engineering, Data Engineering Zoomcamp